此字幕为亲爱的西西宝贝制作，(*^__^*)
-=Xaofei
******       ******
**********   **********
************* *************
*****************************
***************************
***********************
*******************
***************
***********
*******
***
*Cece字幕制作组=-
时间轴:wk120  翻译:飞哥
校对:西西宝贝
720p版本调教：Tears
孩子们当你们单身时
致力于寻找终身幸福
Kids when you are single,all you're
looking for is happily all after.
但是在你经历的所有爱情故事里
只有一次能圆满结局
But only one of your
stories can end that way,
其它的则最终以一方受伤结束
the rest ended with somebody get hurt.
我将讲述的就是一个这样结束的故事
This is one of those stories,
它因为一件衬衫而开始
that starts with a shirt.
- 衬衫?
- 听我说
- A shirt?
- just listen,
要不是那件衬衫
这件事情是不可能发生的
because none of that would have
happened if it hadn't been for that shirt.
- 不错的衬衫
- 是不? 是不?
- nice shirt
- Right? Right?
看看这颜色
绿色和棕色混杂在一起
look at those colors,
green and brown together at last.
新款吗,兄弟?新买的?
hot top,bro? is it new.
最让人疯狂的是
that's the crazy part.
这件衬衫我已经买了6年了
I've had this shirt for 6 years
一直到今天早晨
我完全没有注意到它
until this morning,
I was not into it at ll,
但是现在
就象我的品味改变了
but now,
it's like my tastes changed.
- 鼻屎
- 呃,你好,Barney
- Booger.
- yes,hello,barney.
Barney给我50块钱
让我在直播报道里说些愚蠢的话
barney has offered me 50 bucks to say
some stupid word on a live news report.
不是什么蠢话,鼻屎
not some stupid word,booger.
我还是不会做这个
我是一个新闻记者
But I'm not doing it.
I am aournalist.
什么?!记者?!
What?! Journalist?!
你只是在新闻的最后
做点边角料
You do the little fluff pieces
at the end of the news.
老人 小孩 猴子
Old people. Babies. Monkeys.
这不是新闻工作
只是... 婴儿做的幼稚事
That's not journalism.
That's just... things in a diaper.
你可能还不知道
老板要我到...
For your information,
my boss is about to bump me up to...
- 市政厅
- 市政厅?大人物
- the city hall beat.
- City hall? Miss thing.
我不会为了50块钱去说"鼻屎"
这会危及我的升迁
I'm not going to jeopardize my
promotion by saying "booger" for 50 bucks.
当然不
Of course not.
这回你说"乳头"的话
我将给出100块钱
'Cause now you're saying "nipple,"
and it's a hundred.
进入我的圈套吧
Step into my web.
呃 这是谁的波旁酒？
Mmm. Whose bourbon is this?
喔 我不知道
我们坐下的时候就在这了
Ooh,I don't know.
It was here when we sat down.
啊... 重点是...
Gahhh... the point is...
我现在似乎开始喜欢波旁酒了
I seem to like bourbon now.
我以前发誓讨厌波旁酒
I could've sworn I hated bourbon.
首先是衬衫,现在又是波旁酒
First the shirt,now bourbon.
我花了27年来形成对事物的喜恶,对吗?
I spent 27 years making up
my mind about things,right?
看过一次就讨厌的电影
The movie I saw once and hated;
因为我去的时候在下雨而导致
再也不想去第二次的城市
the city I'll never go back to
'cause it was raining the day I visited.
可能是时候对事物有一个新的看法了
Maybe it's time to start
forming some second impressions.
你终于又看《七宝奇谋》了吗?
You're finally gonna watch goonies again?
"Sloth love chunk.
我不是说《七宝奇谋》 我指女生
Not goonies-- girls.
如果以前有某个女生
What if there's someone from my past
我那时候觉得不适合我
who I thought was wrong for me at the time,
但是其实她,就象这件衬衫
when in fact she,like this shirt,
事实上很适合我?
is actually a perfect fit?
等等
Hold up.
只有两个原因
可以让你去约会以前已经交往过的女生
There are only two reasons to ever
date a girl you'velready dated:
乳房... 移植
Breast... implants.
你知道,这注意不坏
You know,this isn't a bad idea.
让我想想...
Ted以前的女友精选辑
Let's think...
ted's greatest hits.
Steph怎么样?
What about that girl steph?
Steph...
好吧,这有点难说出口
okay,this is difficult to say:
回溯到我住在洛衫机时
我一文不名
Back when I lived in L.A.,
I was pretty broke
因此我花了一个月拍成人电影
so I spent a month making adult films.
哇 好吧...
Wow. Okay...
你拍了多少部?
h-how many did you make?
要说对从事色情业的人的看法
他们辛苦工作
Say what you will about the porn industry,
they're hard workers.
那个女的怎么样 呃...
Jackie?
What about that chick,um...
jackie?
...我的浴袍完全滑下去了
...And my bathing suit
had fallen completely off.
我了解你的感受
有一次
I know the feeling. Once,
我16的时候,开着车
when I was 16,I was driving,
撞上了一个想搭便车的家伙
and I hit this hitchhiker.
我不知道他怎么样了--
只是继续开我的车
Don't know what happened to him--
just kept driving.
呃... 不要
uh... no.
Natalie呢?
What about natalie?
Natalie...
谁是Natalie?
who's natalie?
Natalie
Natalie.
我和她有很多美好的回忆
I had so many fond memories of her:
她茶几上的蜡烛
The tea candles on her dresser,
她床上收集的袜子猴
the sock monkey collection on her bed,
她一直在听的格拉丝高的歌
that one belle & sebastian
song she always listened to,
她的微笑...
her smile...
天那,我有大概3年没见过她了
man,I haven't seen her in,
like,three years.
嗯 你们为什么会分手
Well,why'd you guys break up
那时候我并不想做出承诺
I just wasn't looking for a big
commitment at the time.
当然
现在看来这样并不坏
Of course,
now a big commitment doesn't seem so bad.
也许我应该找她
你们怎么想?
Maybe I should call her.
What do you guys think?
你甩了一个三级明星?
You dumped a porn star?
我们的友谊完了
Friendship over.
我们的友谊完了!
Friendship over!
进来!
come in!
好吧,一会再找我
All right,get back to me,then.
- 你想见我吗 Adam先生
- 是的
- You wanted to see me,mr. Adams.
- Yes,I did.
我需要你去报道一个故事
I need you to cover a story.
就在市政厅那边
It's down at city hall.
市政厅?
City hall?
噢 天那
Oh,my god.
那么 下次当你经过市政厅时
so,next time you're passing city hall,
别忘了找到这个纽约
最古老的热狗贩卖车
make sure and stop by
new york's oldest hot dog cart.
今时今日
一个美味的热狗将花去你2.50元
Today,a delicious hot
dog will cost you $2.50,
但是回溯到1955年
but back when the
stand first opened,in 1955,
你可以仅用一个乳头买到一个热狗
you could get one for only a nipple.
现场直播 Robin Trubotsky
来自都市新闻一台
Reporting live,robin trubotsky,
metro news one.
我在新闻上说了"乳头"
I said "nipple" on the news.
这太不专业了!
我在新闻上说了"乳头"!
That was so unprofessional!
I said "nipple" on the news!
至少比"鼻屎"好
At least it's better than "booger."
鼻屎
booger.
你在这呢
there she is.
嘿,这里很冷吗?
我几乎可以见Robin的钱袋儿了
Hey,is it cold in here?
'Cause I can kinda see robin's nickels.
现在 为了你的下一次挑战...
now,for your next challenge...
不会再有什么挑战了
我不在乎你给出多少钱
there is not going to be another challenge.
I don't care how much you offer me.
噢 扪心自问Robin
Oh,search your soul,robin.
我们都知道这跟钱没有关系
You and I both know this
wasn't about the money.
当然，都市新闻一台付你的薪水，Jack
但是……
Sure,metro news one pays you jack,
and,hey,
多吃点蔬菜沙拉对
对你，我和Mcgee先生都有好处
a little green salad on the side
is good for you,me,and mr. Mcgee.
说真的，谁这么说话？
Seriously,who talks like that?
小宝贝真正得到的……
What baby really likes
给那些工于心计不赏识你
更不会提拔你的人……
is the thrill of pulling one over on
those bean-counters who underappreciate you,
教训一下的刺激感
and still haven't promoted you,
那么为了另外两百大洋
and so for two more hundie sticks,
小宝贝会看这镜头说...
baby's going to look in
the camera and say this.
我只是在设想
M just assuming.
我得回去工作了
I gotta get back to work.
- 回头见
- 拜
- See ya.
- Bye.
小宝贝会去考虑下这个
Baby's gonna think about it.
找到啦!
我找到Natalie的电话了
found it!
I found natalie's number.
嘿 Ted! 不错的衬衫!
又回到昨天了吗?
Hey,ted! Nice shirt!
Is it yesterday already?
我要给她打电话 这有点疯狂
I am calling her. This is crazy.
我大概有3年没跟她讲过话了
I haven't talked to her in,
like,three years.
不知道她是不是还记得我
Wonder if she even remembers me.
- 你好?
- Natalie
- hello?
- Natalie.
- 我是Ted Mosby
- It's ted mosby.
- 去死吧
- Go to hell.
她还记得我
She remembers me.
为什么Natalie挂你电话?
why would natalie hang up on you?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 你和她姐姐睡过了吗?
- 没有
- Did you sleep with her sister?
- No.
- 那你和她妈妈睡过了?
- 也没有
- Did you sleep with her mom?
- No.
我正对你的故事失去兴趣
I'm losing interest in your story.
嗯 你一定做了什么事情她才会这样
Well,you must have done something.
你们为什么分手?
Why did you guys break up?
他还没为做出承诺准备好
He wasn't ready for a commitment.
那时她的生日快到了
And her birthday might've been coming up.
好吧 我不想给一个我即将提出分手的人
okay,so I didn't want to
get a boyfriend-level gift
送一份男朋友级别的礼物
for a girl I was just
about to break up with.
所以你在她生日前甩了她?
So you dumped her
right before her birthday?
不是 我没在生日前甩她
No,I didn't dump her
right before her birthday.
Natalie! 嘿
生日快乐
Natalie! Hey.
Happy birthday.
听着...
Listen...
- 永远都不能在女生的生日那天提出分手!
- Lily 别这样! 衬衫!
- Never break up with a girl on her birthday!
- Lily,please! The shirt!
我知道!我犯了个错误!
I know! It was a mistake!
好吧 她把眼睛给哭肿了吗?
Well,did she cry her eyes out?
- 我不知道
- 你怎么会...?!
- I don't know.
- How do you not...?!
不是吧你
You didn'T.
Natalie! 嘿 生日快乐
Natalie! Hey,happy birthday.
听着...
Listen...
你很不错
you're awesome.
真的不错
You really are.
很不错
Awesome.
我现在很忙 所以...
I'm just like super-busy
right now,so...
也许我们之间还是画上休止符吧
maybe we should just...
call it a day.
但是你很不错
But you're awesome.
在电话答录机上!?
On her answering machine!?
- Lily 别这样
- 在她生日那天?!
- Lily,come on.
- And on her birthday?!
噢 谁会在对方生日那天而且是答录机上提出分手?!
Oh,who breaks up with somebody on
their answering machine on her birthday?!
是啊 兄弟 你该发E-mail说
Yeah,dude. E-mail.
这不是我想表达的重点Marshall
Not exactly the point I
was trying to make,marshall.
这样提出分手太可怕了
That is a terrible way
to break up with someone.
好吧 我为我的当事人辩护
Okay,in my client's defense,
有什么方法与人分手是不可怕的吗?
没有
is there an unterrible way
to break up with somebody? No.
就我个人而言
我宁愿从答录机上听到坏消息...
Personally,I'd rather hear the
bad news on an answering machine...
比面对面觉得丢脸好
这是一种减轻对对方伤害的方法
than face the humiliation in person.
It's the least painful way you can do it.
- 你在给谁打电话?
- 嗨 Marshall 我是Lily
- Who are you calling?
- Hi,marshall,it's lily.
至少一个月内我们不会做爱
We're not gonnhave sex for at least a month,
但是你很不错 好了 拜拜
but you're awesome. Okay,bye-bye.
不 这是一个很大的错误
Ted 你应该当面说分手
No,that was a big mistake,
ted. You should've done it in person.
谢谢
Thank you.
“疯狂绝望的别离开我”性爱
……妙不可言
Desperate,
please-don't-leave-me sex is amazing.
好吧
这很幼稚愚蠢 我只是...
Okay,
it was childish and stupid. I ju...
我不想看见她哭
I didn't want to see her cry.
嗯 猜猜怎么样 她还是哭了
Well,guess what she cried.
你只是没种面对那些眼泪
You just didn't have
the sack to face those tears.
我以前就是那样 好不?
That was me then,okay?
现在是一个崭新的
穿着以前的衬衫的有种的Ted
This is the new,
old-shirt- wearing,sack-having ted.
我要去把这事纠正过来
I'm gonna make this right.
你们知道吗?
我的妹妹...
You know what else?
"My younger sister...
...“新婚而且快三十岁”性爱
...just got married and
I'm about to turn 30" sex.
太棒了
Fantastic.
本来应该值得高兴的事
An occasion that was
supposed to be joyous,
变成了悲剧
因为Ethel和Sadie Margolis
suddenly turned tragic
when ethel and sadie margolis,
纽约最老的一对双胞胎
new york's oldest twins,
在他们的100岁生日那晚
suddenly passed away on this,
突然过世
the eve of their 100th birthday.
我是个下流，下流的女生
I'm a dirty,dirty girl.
现场直播 Robin Trubotsky
来自metro news one
Reporting live,robin trubotsky,
metro news one.
清场
Clear.
Joel Adams在办公室等你
Joel adams wants to see you in his office.
在你说任何事之前
Before you say anything,
我想说我真的很喜欢在这工作
I just want to say I really like
working here at metro news one.
这很好
那么 我的狗一直不停的...
That's great.
So,my dog keeps going
- 这怎么回事...?
- 什么?
- what'S...?
- What?
你也养狗 不是吗?
你觉得这是怎么回事?
You have dogs,right?
What do you think that means?
带他去看兽医?
Take him to the vet?
天才
genius.
我欠你个人情
That's one I owe you.
- 这就是你想说的吗?
- 对啊
- Was that all?
- Yeah.
- 没什么关于那个双胞胎的故事要说的吗?
- 噢 对 你做的不错
- And nothing about the twins story?
- Oh,yeah,great job on that one.
纽约爱你
你是个超级明星 拜拜
New york loves you.
You're a superstar. Bye-bye.
那时候Robin明白了没人
That's when robin
realized that no one
甚至包括她的老板
也不看都市新闻一台
not even her boss,
watched metro news one.
嗨
hi.
Natalie!别这样!
我只想说我很抱歉
natalie! Come on!
I just want to say I'm sorry.
我来这只是因为你不接我电话
I only came down here
'cause you woul't take my call.
嘿 我有个主意--
Hey,here's an idea--
你怎么不用答录机?
why don't you leave a message?
很好笑
good one.
好 好吧 我把这个袜子猴留下就走
Okay,fine,I'm just going
to leave this sock monkey here.
再见
Good-bye.
- 天那
- 没事 没事!
- Oh my god.
- ok,ok!
听着 听着 听着
我知道你很生气 但是...
look,look,look.
I know you're mad,but...
生日快乐 3年前的祝福
happy birthday.Three years ago.
噢 是吗?随你便 3年前
Oh,yeah? Up yours three years ago.
听着听着
给你留那个言我真是个白痴
Look,look,
I was an idiot leaving that message.
我意识到那样有多另人讨厌
I realize how much that sucked.
不 你没有
No,you don'T.
也许我们之间还是画上休止符吧
Maybe we should just call it a day.
但是你很不错
But you're awesome.
好吧 拜
Okay,bye.
惊喜吧
Surprise.
那天晚上有一个惊喜派对吗?
There was a surprise party that night?
为什么没人告诉我?
How come nobody told me?
人们认为我不能保守秘密
但是我完全可以
People think I can't keep a secret,
but I totally can.
抱歉 和这个没关系
Sorry,not the issue.
听着Natalie
Look,natalie,
我那时是一个愚蠢的小孩
害怕做出承诺
I was just a stupid kid back then,
terrified of commitment.
我猜你突然做好准备结婚然安定下来
And I suppose you're suddenly
ready to get married and settle down.
嗯 事实上是的
Well,yeah,actually.
我现在完全不同了
I'm a different guy now.
再给我一次机会
Give me another chance,
你大概觉得我完全没有自尊吧
You must think I have
absolutely no self-respect.
别这样 只是一起喝点咖啡
Come on,just a cup of coffee.
请别这样 Natalie
给他个机会
Please,natalie.
Give the guy a chance.
别太高傲了
Self-respect is overrated.
可能是咖啡因的作用
Maybe it was the caffeine,
你的技巧完全提升了个等级
but you really brought your
game up to a whole new level.
谢谢
Thanks.
我刚刚开始订阅《Esquire》
（时尚杂志）
I did just start subscribing to esquire.
里面有一些很有用的专栏
They have some helpful columns.
接下来的
The following
来自于十月刊
is from the october issue.
我和Natalie又开始约会了
So natalie and i started dating again.
就那样 以前的那些又回来了
And just like that,it all came back.
蜡烛...
The tea candles...
袜子猴...
the sock monkeys...
格拉丝高 所有的这些
belle and sebastian,all of it.
就象幸福离我不远了
It seemed like happily
ever after wasn't far off.
嗯 我得走了
Well,I better run.
半小时后我要去学Krav Maga
I have my krav maga class in half an hour.
Krav Maga
她居然学Krav Maga太酷了
Krav maga.
How cool is it that she does krav maga?
谢谢 亲爱的
Thanks,honey.
- 拜 伙计们
- 拜 拜  慢慢来
- Bye,guys.
- Bye. Bye. Take it easy.
兄弟 什么是Krav Maga?
Dude,what's krav maga?
我也不知道 瑜伽的一种?
I have no idea. Some kind of yoga?
你知道 这就是Natalie
她与时共进
You know,that natalie,
she's good times.
嗯 她是这些年里你约会过的最好的女孩
Yeah,she's,like,
the best girl you've dated in years.
对 Ted 抓住这个
Yeah,ted,hold on to that one.
嗯 我得和她分手
Yeah. I have to break up with her.
我不明白  伙计
Natalie很不错啊
I don't get it,man.
Natalie's awesome.
我知道 她很棒
但是我必须和她分手
I know,she's terrific,
but I have to break up with her.
为什么你不能
不去烦那个可怜的女孩?
Why couldn't you
leave that poor girl alone?
我知道 我讨厌这样
I know. Hate this.
过去3周很我们处的不错
These past three weeks have been great.
我应该爱上她 但是
I should be in love with her,but
我没找到感觉
I'm not feeling that thing.
不知道怎么用语言表达
It's ineffable.
表达不出来 说的好
Ineffable. Good word.
那么你准备什么时候和她分手?
So when are you going to do it?
她现在可能在地铁站了
She's probably on the subway by now.
你可以给她语音信箱留言
You could call her voice mail:
哔! "甩掉" 挂电话 搞定
Beep! "Dumped." Click. DE. No,
我必须面对面去做
I have to do this face-to-face.
我只是
不知道该怎么说
I just,
I don't know what I'm going to say.
"我还没准备好做出承诺"
"I'm not ready for a commitment."
噢 这太老套了
Oh,that's such a cliche.
这不是老套 是经典
It's not a cliche,it's a classic.
在分手规则里这是
"通往天堂的阶梯"
It's the "stairway to heaven"
of breakup lines.
嗯 Natalie应该受到更好的对待
Well, I think natalie deserves better.
更好
分手时没有好不好
Better.
There's no "better" in breaking up.
只有少另人难堪点
There's only "less awful."
分手理由老套就老套
A cliché is a cliché for a reason.
这更让人舒服点
没关系
It's comforting. It doesn't matter.
我已经告诉她我准备好做出承诺了
所以...
I already told her I am
ready for a commitment,so...
噢 天那 没办法逃脱了 我得和她结婚了
oh,my god. There's no way out.
I'm gonna have to marry her.
不 不 我们会帮你摆脱困境
No,no,we're gonna get you out of this.
嗯 这个...
Okay,hoabout...
"这不是你的错 是我的问题"?
"it's not you,it's me"?
几个字-- "你穿牛仔裤显的很胖"
你就可以自由离开
six words-- "you look fat in those jeans."
You're free to go.
Ted你考虑过告诉她事实吗?
Ted,have you considered
telling her the truth?
认真的说 亲爱的
我们男人正在这想办法
seriously,honey,
men are working here.
Ted什么才是事实?
为什么你要和她分手?
Ted,what is the truth?
Why do you want to break up with her?
事实?她不是我要的那个
The truth? She's not the one.
- 那么就那样告诉她
- 噢 你不能告诉她这个
- So tell her that.
- Oh,you can't tell her that.
- 这太恐怖了
- 为什么?
- hat's horrible.
- Why?
这有什么好恐怖的?
What is so horrible about that?
对 这有什么好恐怖的?
她不是我要的那个
Yeah,what is so horrible about that?
She's not the one.
这个听起来很让人伤心吗?
Why is that such a
heartbreaking thing to hear?
一个人找到他的另一半的机会
The chances of one person
being another person's "the one"
大概是60亿分之1
are,like,six billion-to-one.
对啊 这比你中彩票还难
Yeah,you have better
chances of winning the lottery.
完全正确!
如果没中彩票你不会认为是自己的错
Exactly! You wouldn't take it
personally if you lost the lottery.
好吧 伙计 告诉她事实
All right,man,tell her the truth.
她肯定会哭
She's gonna cry.
嗯 他将会处理的象个男人
Yeah,and he's gonna sit there
and he's gonna take it like a man.
我得做的成熟点
I have to do the mature thing.
想谈谈成熟吗?
Want to talk mature?
我刚刚在报道的最后
拍了自己的屁股
I just wrapped up a live
newscast by honking my own boobs.
一个伟大的节目诞生了
And great tv was had by all.
好吧Trubotsky
新的挑战 这个更猛
All right,trubotsky,
new challenge,and this one's big.
钱也更多
But so is the cash reward.
整整1,000块
你听清我说的了吧
For $1,000-- you heard me--
你只要在新闻里做这个
all you have to do is get up
there on the news and do one of these.
这是什么鬼东西?
What the hell is that?
- Ickey舞
- 你做这个的时候，边做边说
- The ickey shuffle.
- And as you do it,you say this:
Elbert "惹人厌" woods
(Elber Ickey Woods,橄榄球星)
（Ickey舞是他的招牌庆祝动作）
Elbert "icky" woods,
孟加拉虎队91年的时候
和你解约真是愚蠢
the bengals were fools
to cut you in '91.
你总共1,525码的冲刺……
Your 1,525 rushing yards and
27次触地得分不会被忘记
your 27 touchdowns
will not be forgotten.
所以Dave Shula教练（在任期间解约了Elbert）
去你妈的还有你的烂牛排店
（离开教练席后，Dave开了牛排餐厅）
So coach dave shula,
screw you and your crappy steakhouse.
写下来给我
Just write it down for me.
有什么好在乎的?
无论如何根本没人在看 对吗?
What do I care? It's not like
anyo's watching,anyway,right?
天那 她肯定会哭
Man,she's gonna cry.
这就是恋爱法则 小子
It's the law of love,chunk.
谢谢你Lily
Thanks,lil.
就那样 第2天晚上 我带Natalie出去吃饭...
So,the next night,I took natalie out to dinner...
去做成熟的事
to do the mature thing.
听着 呃 Natalie
有些话我必须得说
Look,uh,natalie,
there's something I haveo say.
噢 等等 我件事我得先说
Oh,wait,wait. There's
something I have to say first.
今天 工作时 我不只收到一个两个
Today,at work,
I had not one,not two,
而是三个生日蛋糕
所以今晚 我们直接跳过蛋糕吧?
but three birthday cakes.
So tonight,can we just skip the cake?
今天是你生日吗?
Today's your birthday?
对
不 没关系 我没告诉任何人
Yeah. No,it's okay,
I wasn't telling anyone about it.
今天是你生日! 我...
Today's your birthday! I...
我什么都没为你准备
I didn't get you anything.
噢 没关系
Oh,it's okay.
你知道 你已经给了我最好的生日礼物
You know,you've already given me the best present of all.
我又能相信人了
I can trust again.
不用客气
You're welcome.
噢 先生 再来点酒
Oh,sir,much more wine.
Henry
Henry,
作为纽约最老最英俊的马车夫
你见过如此多的事情
as new york's oldest hansom cab driver,
you've seen quite a lot.
在你工作的过去60年里
In your past 60 years on the job,
哪件事是让你最激动的?
what is your most exciting memory?
嗯... 啊 就是这里
Well... ah,this is it.
噢 伙计 要开始了
Oh,boy,here we go.
各位 各位 如果你能停下来看电视
Everyone,everyone,if I may direct your attention to the television.
你将看到一些不可思议的事情
You are about to see something amazing.
后来在我72岁时
And then,in '72,
Mickey Mantle
（纽约扬基队球星）
mickey mantle
第4次坐我的马车
rode my cab for the fourth time.
来吧 宝贝
Come on,baby.
露一手
Bring it home.
但是最让我激动的时刻
But the most exciting moment--
是现在这一刻
that would have to be this one,
right now.
什么?
What?
看看我
我上电视了
Look at me.
I'm on tv.
我从来没想过我能讲自己的故事
I never thought I'd have my story told.
谢谢你Robin Trubotsky小姐
Thank you,
miss robin trubotsky.
谢谢
Thank you.
接着
And right then,
Robin阿姨认识到
她的工作是多么的重要
aunt robin realized how
important her job truly was.
能报道你的故事
我很荣幸，Henry
It's an honor to tell your story,
henry.
你要知道都市新闻一台在传媒业中
也许并不是最好的节目
You know,metro news one may
not be number one in viewership,
但是我很骄傲...
哇!
but this reporter takes pride in...
whoa!
噢...! 噢 天那
我跌到马屎里了!
Oh...! Oh,my god,
I'm covered in horse crap!
噢 天那 弄到我头发上了
Oh,my god,it's in my hair.
你计划的吗?
You planned that?
不是 Marshall
No,marshall.
这已经超越了我的想象
That was beyond my wildest dreams.
那么 如果你去阿拉巴马
So,if you ever come to alabama,
我妈妈会给你煮那些巨大的龙虾
my mom throws the huge crawfish boils,
顺便说下 她很想见你
and she's just dying to meet you,
by the way.
听着Natalie
有些话我必须得说
Look,natalie,
there's something I ha to say,
呃 想不到什么好的方式说这个
and,uh,
there's no good way to say it.
我想分手
I want to break up.
我不认为你就是我要的那个人
I don't think you're the one for me.
我不想浪费你的时间
因为我真的喜欢你
I don't want to waste your time,
because I really like you.
我不想对你做错事
I want to do right by you,
最好的方式就是我应该对你诚实
and I think the best way for
me to do that is just to be honest.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
噢 天那 哭出来吧
Oh,god,just let it out.
只有眼泪能缓解伤痛
They're only tears.
我不是你要的那个?!
I'm not the one for you?!
我很抱歉 我只是...
我 我 我认为成熟的做法是...
I'm sorry,I just... I-I-I
thought thmature thing to do...
- 今天是我生日!
- 是 我知道 我没意识到...
- it's my birthday!
- Yes,I know. I didn't realize...
今天是我生日你却跟我说
我不是你想要的那个人?!
it's my birthday,and you're
telling me I'm not the one for you?!
这真的没什么大不了
It's really not such a big deal.
我是说 这跟你没中彩票一样
I mean,the odds--
it's like you lost the lottery.
噢 跟你约会就象中了彩票?!
Oh,so dating you is
like winning the lottery?!
不 噢 不 噢
我不是那意思
No,no,no,no,
I didn't mean that.
好吧 那问题在哪?!
Okay,so what's the problem?!
我... 我...
I... I...
我不知道怎么解释
I can't explain it.
试一下!
Try!
这是... 不知道怎么表达
It'S... ineffable.
我不能表达?
I'm not effable?
不 不 不 不
No,no,no,no.
"不能表达" 不能表达指解释不了
"Ineffable." Ineffable
means it can't be explained.
- 噢 我很蠢吗?
- 噢 天那 到底怎么了?
- Oh,so I'm stupid?
- Oh,god,what's going on?
好吧 怎么了是你伤了我的心
Okay,what's going on
is you broke my heart
我生日在电话答录机上
over my answering
machine on my birthday,
花了3年忘记你
waited three years
for me to get over you,
你却又找到我 求我与你和好
tracked me down,
begged me to go out th you again,
只是为了你能在3周后甩掉我
only so you could
dump me three weeks later,
再一次在我生日时候!
again,on my birthday!
不 这 这 这不象你想的那样
我只是...
No,it's-it's-it's not like that.
I'm just...
这 这 这 是...
it's-it's-it'S...
- 什么?!
- 我只是 只是现在很忙
- what?!
- I'm just,like,so busy right now.
记得Natalie说...
Remember when natalie said...
半小时后我有Krav Maga课
I have my krav maga
class in half an hour.
Krav Maga并不是瑜伽的一种
Turns out krav maga
is not a kind of yoga.
是以色列军队发明的
用于街头游击战的拳术
It's a form of guerilla street
fighting developed by the israeli army.
这是吧台那两位绅士的致敬
This is compliments of those
two gentlemen at the bar.
- 我的膝盖!
- 弄到我头发上了!
- My knee!
- It's in my hair!
知道人们在看这节目
不值得高兴吗?
But isn't nice to
know people are watching?
噢 天那 你还好吧?
Oh,my god. Are you all right?
你怎么了?
Wh happened to you?
我说出了事实
I told the truth.
事实意味着一记大抡拳
Turns out the truth has
a mean roundhouse kick.
噢 伙计
Oh,man.
噢 你做对了 我为你骄傲
Oh,well,you did the right thing.
I'm proud of you.
我的心在滴血
I'm bleeding internally.
嘿Ted你知道当我失落的时候
什么让我振作起来吗?
Hey,ted,you know what always
picks me up when I'm down?
其他人的不幸
Other people's misfortune.
你错过了精彩的事
You missed something so amazing.
天那 整个酒吧就不能留一个
没看到我的糗事的人吗?
Please,can we just have one person
in this whole bar who didn't see it?
好吧
Fine.
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
我真的觉得我这次用了很好的方式
I really thought I was doing
it the good way this time.
我猜根本就没有什么好的方法
I guess there is no good way.
有时候 不管你多努力去做正确的事情
Sometimes,no matter how
hard you try to do the right thing,
最终也以摔倒结束
you just end up flat on your back,
摔倒在一堆马屎上
flailing around in a
big pile of horse crap.
- 你看到了?
- 我的电话现在能上网
- You saw it?
- My phone gets the internet now.
没关系
Is OK
这就是我和Natalie故事的结局
And that's how it ended with natalie.
没有永远幸福快乐
No happily ever after,
只有伤害
just a whole lot of hurt.
就这样
Anjust like that,
所有的愉快回忆被取代...
all those wonderful
memories were replaced...
被这些伤害取代
by this one.
但是 你知道吗
But,you kw,
那个晚上太糟糕了
bad as that night was,
不到一年
Natalie就结婚了
within a year,
natalie was married.
现在她有3个美丽的小孩
And now she has three beautiful children.
这是受伤害的积极的一面
So that's the upside of hurt.
有时候因为某些原因而发生
Sometimes it happens for a reason.
你被一个女生痛揍了?
So you got beat up by a girl?
这就是你从这个故事里学到的吗?
Is that all you're
taking away from this story?
你被一个女生痛揍了
You got beat up by a girl.
嘿 她学过Krav Maga
Hey,she knew krav maga.
" 老爸老妈的罗漫史 第1季 第4集"
-=END=-
" How i met your mother Season 01 EP 04 "